ILGWU Local 98 Records 5780/077
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU Local 98 Records
1938-1983
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Pokodner, Herbert
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 98
International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU)
5780/077
4 cubic feet
4 linear ft.
Records (documents), minutes (administrative records).
The collection contains meeting minutes of Local 98's Executive Board, Manager Herbert Pokodner's correspondence, and company files that document the union's organizing and service efforts.
6322438
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
D. Mordente, February 25, 2009
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.
Biographical / Historical
Local 98 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as the Rubberized Plastic Fabric Workers' Union, was based in New York, New York.
Scope and Contents
The first series consists of minutes from the Executive Board meetings. The second series contains correspondence of Local 98 manager Herbert Pokodner, arranged alphabetically by subject. Much involves the administration of Local 98 and its members, and covers such topics as the Health and Welfare Funds, Union Health Center, Retirement Services, and various departments within the union.
There is much correspondence with other locals; discussing the transfer of a member to their local; invitations to events or activities of other locals; contract negotiations and new agreements--all illustrating the unique relationship between Local 98 and its rubberized plastic and fabric workers to the industry as a whole and how its manufacturing and production also correlated with the garment production of other locals.
Organizations mentioned include: Brooklyn Histadrut, City of Hope, Hispanic Labor Committee, Jewish Labor Committee, Workmen's Circle; Correspondents include: Sol Chaikin, Wilbur Daniels, James Lipsig, Gus Tyler, Louis Stulberg.
The third series consists of company files and contains correspondence, National Labor Relations Board cases and agreements.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records
Arrangement
Series I: Executive Board minutes
Series II: Herbert Pokodner's correspondence
Series III: Company files
Plastics workers--Labor unions--United States.; Chaikin, Sol C.; Daniels, Wilbur; Dubrow, Evelyn; Lipsig, James; Pokodner, Hebert; Stulberg, Louis, 1901-1977; Tyler, Gus; AFL-CIO. New York City Central Labor Council; Amalgamated Bank of New York; Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union; American Trade Union Council for Histadrut; American Veterans Committee; Central Labor Rehabilitation Council N.Y.; Hispanic Labor Committee; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 98; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Educational Department; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Engineering Department; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. New York Cloak Joint Board; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 10-22-60-89; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Legal Department; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 1-S (Dept. Store Workers); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 20 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 22 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 23-25 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 32 (Winnipeg, Man.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 40; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 62 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 66 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 91 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 99; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 105 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 132; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 155 (New York, N.Y.); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 600; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Local 98; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Political Dept.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Research Dept.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Union Label Dept.; Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.); Lieberman, Aronson & Rosenberg; Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company; National Trade Union Council for Human Rights; New York (State). Board of Mediation; New York State AFL-CIO; United States. Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service
6322438
- Series Series I: Executive Board minutes
  - Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1938-1946 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1938-1946 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1946-1953 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1946-1953 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Executive Board Minutes, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1957-1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Executive Board Minutes [folder 1 of 2], 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Executive Board Minutes [folder 2 of 2], 1964-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series Series II: Herbert Pokodner's correspondence
  - American Labor ORT Correspondence, 1974-1980 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - American Trade Council for Histadrut Correspondence, 1970-1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - American Veterans Committee Correspondence and Reservation Form, 1975-1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Amalgamated Bank Stop Payments and Checks, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Shelley Appleton, General Secretary and Treasurer. Correspondence, 1978-1981 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Beame Campaign Materials, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Blood Bank Notices, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Blue Cross Form Letters, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - B'nai B'rith Teamsters Lodge 2201 Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Central Labor Rehabilitation Council Correspondence, 1971-1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Histadrut Council Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Central States Region Letter, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - President Chaikin's Humanitarian Award Dinner Materials, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - President Sol Chaikin Materials, 1973-1982 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Circulation Department, ILGWU. Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Human Resource Administration. Department of Income Maintenance Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - City of Hope, Pilot Medical Center. Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Collected Wages Form, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Consumer Assembly. Letters to Members, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Wilbur Daniels Correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - NYC Department of Social Services, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Deborah Hospital Contribution Letters, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Evelyn Dubrow Materials, 1970-1980 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Education Department, ILGWU Materials, 1968-1982 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Eastern Region Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - "El Diario" Advertisement, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Electric Typewriter Purchase Information, Sample and Instructions, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Engineering Department, ILGWU. Materials, 1970-1978 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service Correspondence with Rubberized Novelty and Plastic Fabric Workers' Union, 1951-1976 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Federal Trade Commission Letter, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Form File and Correspondence, 1957-1976 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Hispanic Labor Committee Correspondences, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Central Organizing Department, Investigational Report, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - ILGWU National Scholarship Fund Materials, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Mailing Department, ILGWU. Notice, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - ILGWU Retiree Service Correspondence, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - ILGWU Union Health Center Social Service Program Materials, 1976-1978 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - ILGWU Union Health Center Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Fair Trade Practices Department, ILGWU. Import Manual and Materials, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Jewish Labor Committee Correspondence, 1970-1982 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Cloak Joint Board, ILGWU. Invitations, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Joint Board Dress and Waistmakers' Union Invitations, 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Local 98 & "Justice" Newsletter Correspondence, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - ILGWU Southeast Region Letter, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Labor Council for Latin American Advancement Correspondence, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Labor Day Parade Materials, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - League for Industrial Democracy, Inc., 1974 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Legal Department, ILGWU. Correspondence, 1971-1982 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Lieberman, Katz and Aronson Correspondence, 1970-1978 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - James Lipsig Correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Department Workers' Union, Local 1-S. Contribution Letter, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Cutters' Union, Local 10. Miscellaneous, 1971-1980 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Waterproof Garment Workers' Union, Local 20 Miscellaneous, 1971-1975 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Cloakmakers' Union, Local 21 Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Dressmakers' Union of Manhattan, Local 22 Miscellaneous, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers' Union, Local 23-25 Miscellaneous, 1970-1983 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Corset and Brassiere Workers' Union, Local 32 Miscellaneous, 1970-1977 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Belt Makers', Novelty and Allied Workers' Union, Local 40 Miscellaneous, 1971-1982 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Rubberized Novelty and Plastic Fabric Workers' Union, Local 98 Miscellaneous, 1969-1981 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Local 66, ILGWU Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Local 85, ILGWU Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Dress, Rainwear and Allied Workers' Union of Brooklyn and Staten Island, Local 89 Correspondence with Local 98, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Childrens Dress, Infant Wear, Housedress and Bathrobe Makers' Union, Local 91 Miscellaneous, 1975-1980 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Office and Distribution Employees' Union, Local 99 Miscellaneous, 1970-1978 (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Snowsuit, Skiwear, Leggings and Infants' Novelty Wear Workers' Union, Local 105 Miscellaneous, 1950-1982 (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Plastic, Moulders and Novelty Workers' Union, Local 132 Miscellaneous, 1967-1983 (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Knitgoods Workers' Union, Local 155 Miscellaneous, 1971-1980 (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Locals 144,166 and 222 Correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Local 148-162 Correspondence, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Local 161 Correspondence, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - Local 415 Correspondence, 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Local 600 Correspondence, 1970-1977 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Los Angeles Joint Board. Luz Lopez Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Manufacturers' Hanover Trust Company Correspondence, 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Robert Markewich Correspondence, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Mayor's Committee on Exploitation of Workers Correspondence, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Members' Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Members' Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1970-1978 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - National Trade Union Council for Human Rights, 1971-1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - New England Region Correspondence, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - New Jersey State Board of Mediation Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - NYC Central Labor Council Memorandum and Correspondence, 1971-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - NY Coat, Suit, Dress, Rainwear and Allied Workers' Union Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - New York Committee for Labor Youth Letters, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - New York Labor Management Council of Health and Welfare Plans, Inc. Letters and Memorandum, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - State of New York, Department of Labor Correspondence and Materials, 1973-1975 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - New York State District, ILGWU Correspondence, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - New York State AFL-CIO Miscellaneous Documents, 1972-1982 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - New York State Board of Mediation Correspondence, 1962-1975 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Northeast, Western Pennsylvania and Ohio Department Invitations to Unity House, 1974-1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - "Old Timers" Notices, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - George Ostrow Retirement Reception and Luncheon, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Plastic Fabric Workers Union Local 98, ILGWU Membership Meeting Minutes, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Philadelphia Dress Joint Board, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Political Department, ILGWU Election Materials and Correspondence [folder 1 of 2], 1970-1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Political Department, ILGWU Election Materials and Correspondence [folder 2 of 2], 1970-1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Puerto Rican Day Parade Notices, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Rubberized Novelty and Plastic Workers' Union Correspondence, 1954-1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Socialist Party-Democratic Socialist Federation, USA, 1972-1979 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Southeast Region, ILGWU Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Spanish Language Center of New York Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Sportswear and Allied Workers' Joint Board Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Research Department, ILGWU Correspondence and Collective Bargaining Agreements, 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Siems, Frederick R. Memorandums, 1977-1979 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Tyler, Gus. Correspondence, 1970-1980 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Stulberg, Louis. Correspondence, 1969-1976 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Tannen, Eli. Correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Pokoder, Herbert. Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Union Label and Service Council Correspondence, 1972-1980 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Trade Union Council of the Bund Archives Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Union Label Department, ILGWU Correspondence, 1971-1982 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - U.S. Department of Labor Wage and Hour and Public Contract Division Correspondence, 1967-1971 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Upper South Department, ILGWU Correspondence, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Wage Freeze Articles and Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Wolf and Schulman Correspondence with Herbert Pokoder, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Workmen's Circle Home and Infirmary for the Aged Correspondence with Herbert Pokodner, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - A and A Novelties Company Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Acme Publishing Company, Inc. Notices and Applications for Membership, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Agora International Application for Membership, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - A and G Manufacturers, Inc. Notices for Membership, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Series Series III: Company files
  - A and J Manufacturing Company Report, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Aldan Sundries, Inc. Miscellaneous, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Alexander Shields Fabrica de Obreros Organizados Notices, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    Scope and Contents
    Spanish
  - Allied Sundries Company Letter to Members, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Ambros Novelty Stitching Company, Inc. Miscellaneous, 1954-1962 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    English and Spanish
  - American Portfolio Company, Inc. Analytical Report, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - American Felt Slipper Company, Inc. Profile and Report, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Art Textile Products Report and Correspondence, 1949-1961 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Ashland Production Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Aquador Plastics Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Best Seal Corporation Applications for Membership and Correspondence, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Ballerina Glove Runaway Union Shop Notices, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Bentley Manufacturing Corporation Financial Reports, 1946-1962 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Benton Packaging Notices to Unionize (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - J.L. Dannenberg and Company Applications for Membership, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Best Curtain Company Correspondence, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - J and M Bindery Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Boro-Heat Sealed Novelties Correspondence, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Max Brooks Company Correspondence, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Brooks and Company Notices, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Bucksen Inc. Notices, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Capital Plastics, Inc. Miscellaneous, 1956-1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Carlan Inc. Business Information Reports, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Caren Sue Undergarment Company Notice, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - C and C Specialty Company Financial Reports, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Celebrity Inc., Notices and Correspondence, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - The Cello Company Correspondence, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Century Products, Inc. Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Century Products, Inc. Miscellaneous, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Certified Fabrics Miscellaneous, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Nat Berger d/b/a Cleartex Company and Local 98 Agreement, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Climax Rubber Company Unionization Materials, 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Chanal Plastic Corporation Petition for Certification and Membership Applications, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Crest Hangers Correspondence, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Crusader Addresses (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Colortex Inc. Notes (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Columbia Manufacturing Company Advertisement (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Coronet Manufacturing Company Agreement with Local 98, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - C-Thru Products, Inc. Public Record Information, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - CW Novelty Manufacturing Company Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Del-Pen Notices, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Deutsch Brothers Union Notices, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Dora May Company, Inc. Miscellaneous, 1950-1966 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Doran Scarf and Novelty Company Petition for Unionization, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Dorothy and Mercer Curtain Manufacturing Company Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Duplex Curtain Company Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Dura Plastron Company letter, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Dura Wear Manufacturing Company Applications for Membership, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Edmac Draperies Inc., Notices, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Falani and Cohn Inc., Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Frank Logan Shop Correspondence, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Franklin Plastic Novelties Financial Report, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - S. Frelirich Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Gailyn Packaging Company Miscellaneous, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - G and G Novelties Applications for Membership and Correspondence, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Glen Designs and Glenco Miscellaneous, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Guild Plastics Unionization Notices, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Goodyear Plastics Notices, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Plastictronics, Inc. Applications for Membership and Notices, 1953 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - James G. Hardy and Company Financial Reports, 1958-1962 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Heat Sealing Novelties Company, Inc. Business Information Report, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Home Curtain Company Unionization Notices and Correspondence, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - House Beautiful Curtains Miscellaneous, 1951-1957 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - House of Schiller Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - International Flouncing Corporation Notices and Applications for Membership, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Inez Holland House, Inc. Unionization Materials, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Iona Plastic Products, Inc. Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Package Manufacturers Inc. Union Cards, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Paragon Art and Linen Company, Miscellaneous [folder 1 of 2], 1949-1959 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Paragon Art and Linen Company, Miscellaneous [folder 2 of 2], 1949-1959 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Parker-Stern Company Correspondence, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Paris Queen Bags, Inc. Notice, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Pelamay Products Miscellaneous, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Pelamay Plastics Reports, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Penguin Manufacturing Company Letter, 1949 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Phoenix Closet Accessories Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Plasticloth Products, Inc. Contract, 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Plastic and Excellent Art Manufacturing Company Reports, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Plastix Corporation of America Correspondence, 1946 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - Progress Heat Sealing Company Report, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - J. Radley Metzger Miscellaneous, 1948-1950 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Rafer Inc. Report, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Real Curtains, Inc. Miscellaneous, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Red Raven Rubber Company, Inc. Miscellaneous, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Reliable Plastics Company Reports and Notices, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Republic Packaging Company Miscellaneous, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Riviera Trading Corporation Report, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Rona Plastics Corporation and W.P. Finishing Corporation Union Cards, 1954 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Ross Plastics Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Roto-Lith Notice for Unionization, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 69)